[{"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a94", "question": "Who had a flying carpet?", "answer": "Aladdin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e1", "question": "Who directed and acted in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9391c6bd93ce3a4e5f689", "question": "In 2012, what new molecule was discovered by a 10-year old in science class?", "answer": "Tetranitratoxycarbon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e1", "question": "What color was Tweety Bird originally?", "answer": "Pink", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394ae", "question": "Who created the TV series \"Twin Peaks\"?", "answer": "David Lynch and Mark Frost", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a899d1360d398dc9cf7a6a9", "question": "John F. Kennedy Airport was originally named what?", "answer": "Idlewild Airport", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb5ebf5dad637d903c8825", "question": "Bolivia is home to Salar de Uyuni which is the largest what in the world?", "answer": "Salt flat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b99d", "question": "Which US state's two letter postal abbreviation is \"HI\"?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96a7423c87fd04dd15e12", "question": "As of 2020, which astronaut had spent the most time in space?", "answer": "Gennady Padalka", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e9", "question": "On a standard computer keyboard, what letter is to the right of the letter K?", "answer": "L", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba1f", "question": "In golf, what is the traditional name for a number 3 wood?", "answer": "Spoon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34d", "question": "What is the second largest continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c79efbde8045e48466c5", "question": "Studies show dogs can see which two colors?", "answer": "Dogs can make out combinations of blue and yellow, which may explain why they prefer toys in these colors.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cd3f6e347d002c297e4ac", "question": "Who painted \"The Persistence of Memory\"?", "answer": "Salvador Dali", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f6e", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Fred Jones?", "answer": "The Mystery Machine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600243ad4be4723ccac22199", "question": "Which American author wrote the novel \"The Color Purple\"?", "answer": "Alice Walker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea34acff048f679a45aaf9", "question": "What unit of measure is used to quantify radioactive element activity?", "answer": "Becqueral", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c431", "question": "What is a group of dolphins called?", "answer": "A pod or a school", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f7", "question": "Who was the first Toronto Blue Jay player to lead the American league in home runs?", "answer": "Jesse Barfield", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b0", "question": "Who was the first woman to win an Oscar Best Actress in 1929?", "answer": "Janet Gaynor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d6", "question": "What is Canada's popular winter ice sport that is not hockey?", "answer": "Curling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b6", "question": "How many sides does a trapezoid have?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede1eb6ce05a3942286dc8", "question": "In \"Frosty the Snowman\", what are Frosty's eyes made of?", "answer": "Coal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f5", "question": "What animal has been called the \u201cpoor man\u2019s cow\u201d?", "answer": "The goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0af", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Beggars Banquet\"?", "answer": "Rolling Stones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe765f7eec85e375820b27a", "question": "Which famous figures are featured on Prague\u2019s astronomical clock?", "answer": "The 12 Apostles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a15f", "question": "Who sang the theme to James Bond film \"For Your Eyes Only\"?", "answer": "Sheena Easton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a478", "question": "Lanzarote is part of which island group?", "answer": "The Canaries", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b55a", "question": "What is the Blackberry bush also called?", "answer": "Bramble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5be57f565415ba52ed6f0aa9", "question": "Harris, Lewis and Donegal examples of what fabric?", "answer": "Tweed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7f3", "question": "Which month's name is derived from the Latin word for eight?", "answer": "October", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e0", "question": "What word means a British village without a church?", "answer": "Hamlet", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8b6", "question": "What's the more common name for \"vertical banded gastroplasty\"?", "answer": "Stomach stapling", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59523d60736d4be723796b41", "question": "What is Canada\u2019s motto?", "answer": "From Sea to Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133900a", "question": "In what Agatha Christie book does Hercule Poriot die?", "answer": "Curtain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd3", "question": "Who designed suits for Christian Bale's character in the movie \"The Dark Knight\"?", "answer": "Giorgio Armani", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984e", "question": "What is the name of the villain from the movie \"Mulan\"?", "answer": "Shan Yu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0de8bfcbed638185eaa16", "question": "In which US state is Crater Lake found?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7cf01877e98cb97778a49", "question": "Where is the \"Cathedral of Rum\"?", "answer": "Puerto Rico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b524e662d71a53650ff5", "question": "Born Edgar Poe, where did the middle name Allan come from?", "answer": "It was his adoptive parents' name.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f74b0a9e54d890926f6fd", "question": "In St. Louis, Missouri, it\u2019s illegal for a firefighter to rescue whom?", "answer": "Undressed women (even if they are wearing a nightgown)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bfdfef3b668d7dfe168b5b2", "question": "In 1979 what did President Carter apologise to Australia about?", "answer": "Skylab falling on their country", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe771a2eec85e375820b2fb", "question": "What does a flower worn behind a woman's right ear mean in Hawaii?", "answer": "She's single", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f6", "question": "Which country and western singer is best remembered for her recording of \"Crazy\"?", "answer": "Patsy Cline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339154", "question": "In \"The Saint\" series of books, what is Inspector Teal's full name?", "answer": "Claud Eustace Teal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a96e20565ad31a57c803", "question": "Where did President Franklin D. Roosevelt die?", "answer": "Warm Springs, Georgia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe522321bf59ab7d2e380e5", "question": "Who is the godmother of Kurt Cobain and Courtney Love's kid Francis Bean?", "answer": "Drew Barrymore", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab10", "question": "Which sea lies west of mainland Greece?", "answer": "Ionian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3709ff048f679a45ab13", "question": "What is a nocturnal, giraffe-like animal from the African rainforests called?", "answer": "Okapi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e851fe83fe1f2a824bda", "question": "What were the four humours that the ancient Greeks believed made up the body and determined illness?", "answer": "Blood, phlegm, black bile, yellow bile", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339773", "question": "What is the name of the demons in Hellraiser?", "answer": "Cenobites", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfcc", "question": "What colour is Creme de menthe?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59636c4c967692ea851899a9", "question": "What beer brand shares a name with one of the Founding Father of the United States?", "answer": "Samuel Adams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87a", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"La Rambla\"?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a728c626bcd28c119383285", "question": "What year was the first edition of \"The Guinness Book of Records\" published?", "answer": "1955", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9057701dd7bf43be5e87c", "question": "What does \u00a0\"alea iacta est\" translate into?", "answer": "The die is cast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c654877e98cb977789b7", "question": "The Semper Opera House is located where?", "answer": "Dresden, Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ff", "question": "Lucille Fay LeSueur became famous as who?", "answer": "Joan Crawford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc105b469bb8041d07a06d", "question": "What popular holiday beverage contains sugar, milk and eggs?", "answer": "Eggnog", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c9b49076251badbead8", "question": "Who was the first American to orbit the Earth?", "answer": "John Glenn -- He orbited the Earth three times in five hours in a Mercury space capsule he named \"Friendship 7\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9b99a364247bf200fb88e", "question": "Ostraconophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Shellfish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015ddfffe83fe1f2a824b68", "question": "What conflict was instigated by Aristagoras of Miletus?", "answer": "Persian War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f7a", "question": "What did Aristotle claim as the most delicate of table meats?", "answer": "Camel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f32d01dd7bf43be5e815", "question": "What does SPF stand for?", "answer": "Sun Protection Factor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133897c", "question": "How many puppies did Missis Pongo give birth to in the book \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "15", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f29901dd7bf43be5e811", "question": "What is the process of raising silkworms and making silk called?", "answer": "Sericulture", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b6e", "question": "Who are the three Bronte sisters?", "answer": "Charlotte, Emily and Anne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f36", "question": "What's the protagonist's name in the 1931 movie \"Little Caesar\"?", "answer": "Rico", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99adb21a8909e5c332d25", "question": "What is the Kelvin scale used to measure?", "answer": "Temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8d", "question": "Who crossed the Delaware River on Christmas Eve in 1776 to catch the German Hessians celebrating Christmas?", "answer": "Gen. Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c6d70775fa611bce67d3", "question": "What popular 1990s toy was banned from the U.S. National Security Agency's HQ?", "answer": "Furby -- It had a recording and repeating function. It could be a problem in a place full of confidential material.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c534", "question": "A pluot is a hybrid of what two fruits?", "answer": "Plum and apricot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ae", "question": "Which effect makes the average Earth's temperature around 15 degrees centigrade?", "answer": "The greenhouse effect", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcba", "question": "What model was married to musician Seal?", "answer": "Heidi Klum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab5a", "question": "What sea does the river Elbe flow into?", "answer": "North Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c70", "question": "Sylvester Stallone was born in which US city?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbe8", "question": "How many years did it take to build The Taj Mahal?", "answer": "22 years", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339932", "question": "The 1994 movie \"Quiz Show\" centered around the scandal of what 1950\u2019s game show?", "answer": "Twenty One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a612", "question": "Which is the third largest Caribbean island?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac3f", "question": "What Roman god is January named for?", "answer": "Janus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d61", "question": "Who played the role of TV's J. J. Evans?", "answer": "Jimmie Walker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbe5", "question": "What English Earl's name is now associated with a type of sweater?", "answer": "Earl of Cardigan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff20fdb31a458464a93c437", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Tarzan of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Edgar Rice Burroughs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f7070a9e54d890926f6d6", "question": "Which river carved the Grand Canyon?", "answer": "Colorado River -- Five to six million years ago, the river carved through sediment and volcanic rock to form the Grand Canyon.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab13cbbaab681b0929216e", "question": "In the automotive world, what does the abbreviation CVT stand for?", "answer": "Continuously Variable Transmission", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ce", "question": "Which one of your toes is also known as your \"hallux\"?", "answer": "Big toe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae0", "question": "What small carrier attached to a motorcycle shares its name with a brandy cocktail?", "answer": "Sidecar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c40e", "question": "A Roman nose is notable for its prominent what?", "answer": "Bridge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be3", "question": "During the 1st and 2nd centuries AD, which language was used to write the New Testament?", "answer": "Greek", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e95487ccba3ffe45786dd", "question": "What country are you most likely to hear its residents speak Malagasy?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba84", "question": "What early heavyweight boxing champion was nicknamed the \u201cManassa Mauler\u201d?", "answer": "Jack Dempsey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d47482f8e329de4f87789d", "question": "Who was the Prime Minister of the UK throughout the 1980s?", "answer": "Marget Thatcher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f3e801dd7bf43be5e81a", "question": "SCOTUS stands for what?", "answer": "Supreme Court of The United States", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a64142ebb971c1417fba0", "question": "The song \"I Talk to the Trees\" comes from what musical?", "answer": "Paint Your Wagon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef91f56ce05a3942286e7e", "question": "Which famous writer had a pet raven named Grip?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc842a078d18506ae1fe48d", "question": "Who was the front for the British band \"Culture Club\"?", "answer": "Boy George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a43c", "question": "The Orient Express train originally ran from Paris to where?", "answer": "Istanbul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59029feccad1ec93f27df766", "question": "What country does the cappuccino originate from?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f1", "question": "Who gained notoriety in 1997 for her relationship with Vili Fualaau?", "answer": "Mary Kay Letourneau", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca2f", "question": "Laetrile is most often associated with the pit of which fruit?", "answer": "Apricot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea6", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Zoe, Hammy and Wren?", "answer": "Baby Blues", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a419", "question": "What Scottish landmark borders on Fort Augustus?", "answer": "Loch Ness", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c7", "question": "A silk-screened print is also known as what?", "answer": "Serigraph", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b360", "question": "What were the wicks in the Vestal Virgins lamps allegedly made from?", "answer": "Asbestos", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f457caf848b908361b873", "question": "Who became president of Brazil in 2019?", "answer": "Jair Bolsonaro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f6", "question": "What age followed the Bronze Age?", "answer": "The Iron Age", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7bd3d877e98cb97778957", "question": "What is the flattest continent?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f2", "question": "What note is the highest string of a violin usually tuned to?", "answer": "E", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339367", "question": "What model car did Thelma and Louise drive?", "answer": "Ford Thunderbird", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c948", "question": "What does a Geophage do?", "answer": "Eats earthy substances", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d24", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Breaking Away\"?", "answer": "Bicycle racing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cc", "question": "What US state capital took its name from the French for \"red stick\"?", "answer": "Baton Rouge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a783", "question": "What is the tallest mountain in the world that is not part of the Himalayas or the Andes?", "answer": "Mt. McKinley", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a71", "question": "What is the name of the girl Bruce Springsteen is singing to in the song \"Born to Run\"?", "answer": "Wendy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df2", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"commando\"?", "answer": "Afrikaans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a99820565ad31a57c807", "question": "Who said, \"The buck stops here\"?", "answer": "Present Harry Truman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4cf", "question": "What name is given to trees that lose their leaves annually?", "answer": "Deciduous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe36e5c0ada16518afdc044", "question": "What temperature should you not exceed when melting chocolate?", "answer": "120 F or 49 C", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea41a9ff048f679a45ab70", "question": "What is the chemical term for a peptide; two amino acids linked together?", "answer": "An Amide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909caf5bb53d1af658864d4", "question": "What year did Hallmark made its first Christmas cards?", "answer": "1915", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f1648d3f9b80650dbe7f928", "question": "What Disney movie was the song \"Speechless\" featured in?", "answer": "Aladdin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae8f", "question": "In which US state was President Bill Clinton born?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b571c6767df192a942e3374", "question": "What three countries border the Togolese Republic?", "answer": "Ghana, Benin and Burkina Faso", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad6c", "question": "Which US president had a sign on his desk that read \"The Buck Stops Here\"?", "answer": "Harry Truman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a8", "question": "What song is most famous for its suggestive chorus of \"Voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)\"?", "answer": "Lady Marmalade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4f", "question": "Who was the son of Zeus and Maia?", "answer": "Hermes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a714", "question": "What is the only major port city in Alabama?", "answer": "Mobile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf3f", "question": "What is a gondola?", "answer": "Venetian rowing boat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaab", "question": "Ankara is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133955d", "question": "What is the sport in the movie \"Field of Dreams\"?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067b19ff9c0647b50a8060", "question": "The Gotthard Base Tunnel, which opened on June 1, 2016, is located in which country?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff25b8031a458464a93c478", "question": "In what year was the McDonald's Happy Meal created?", "answer": "Originally fielded in 1977 and ultimately released nationwide in 1979", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c7c", "question": "What famous person was the book editor at Doubleday from 1978 to 1994?", "answer": "Jackie Kennedy (Onassis)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c632", "question": "What is the atomic number of nickel?", "answer": "28", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c65b", "question": "How many moons does Mars have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339533", "question": "Who was Larry Sanders' sidekick on \"The Larry Sanders Show\"?", "answer": "Hank Kingsley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3c6344f0f6af5b066630", "question": "Nuclear membrane, cytoplasm, and nucleus are parts of a what?", "answer": "Cell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc97", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Cesta\"?", "answer": "Jai alai", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5db03eddaa1c9af2684d79a5", "question": "In the classic fighting game series \"Street Fighter\", what does the move \"Shoryuken\" mean in Japanese?", "answer": "Rising Dragon Punch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc8", "question": "Beavis and Butthead worked part-time where?", "answer": "Burger World", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a396", "question": "What is the official language of Papua New Guinea?", "answer": "English", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c4", "question": "In The Simpsons, who does Homer accidentally shoot out of a torpedo tube?", "answer": "Captain Tenille", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae1c", "question": "How many battleships were sunk during the attack of Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "5", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4de1406d333868d34d70e", "question": "Mustafa Kemal was the first President of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cc7a877e98cb97778a26", "question": "Where was Breakneck Ridge in World War II?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b142", "question": "What American won the Nobel Peace Prize in 2007?", "answer": "Al Gore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb96", "question": "What company has a mascot named Poppin' Fresh?", "answer": "Pillsbury", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c802877e98cb977789db", "question": "What Spanish-speaking nation got its name from its position on the Equator?", "answer": "Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523c4c736d4be723796b37", "question": "What is the name of the highway that travels through all ten Canadian provinces?", "answer": "Trans-Canada Highway, or Route Transcanadienne", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c9", "question": "The eggs of what sturgeon are the preferred form of caviar?", "answer": "Beluga", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdabadc0b8cce1e6fda7058", "question": "Which country does the chorizo sausage originate from?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae5d", "question": "What 1980\u2019s US president survived an assassination attempt?", "answer": "Ronald Regan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937ebe308d98002fdd633b4", "question": "What is the study of human behaviour and mind called?", "answer": "Psychology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede3b36ce05a3942286dd5", "question": "In what hotel does Ben rendezvous with Mrs. Robinson in \"The Graduate\"?", "answer": "The Taft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c20", "question": "How did artist, Sting, earn his nickname?", "answer": "By wearing a black and yellow sweater", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133915f", "question": "Who is C3-PO's sidekick?", "answer": "R2-D2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25bb8b63e5727cf5a485b", "question": "What year did the British band EMF release the hit single \"Unbelieveable\"?", "answer": "1990", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc4a", "question": "What item of clothing was Ralph Lauren's first product?", "answer": "A necktie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da5", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Being There\"?", "answer": "Jack Warden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e73206d333868d34d73b", "question": "What was the \"Seven Foot Pilum\" in the Roman arsenal of weapons?", "answer": "A javelin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee5", "question": "What future \"Grey's Anatomy\" costar played Sandra Oh's lover in the movie \"Under the Tuscan Sun\"?", "answer": "Kate Walsh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b6bde662d71a5365100d", "question": "Who named a urinal \"Fountain\" and exhibited it in 1917?", "answer": "Marcel Duchamp", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c2e", "question": "What popular cocktail does James Bond likes \"shaken, not stirred\"?", "answer": "The Martini", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96cce23c87fd04dd15e28", "question": "Who was the first woman to circumnavigate the globe?", "answer": "Jeanne Baret", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339054", "question": "What was the name of Sherlock Holmes' intelligent brother?", "answer": "Mycroft", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a20f", "question": "Jason Voorhees first appeared in the nightmare of which \"Friday the 13th\" character?", "answer": "Alice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133901b", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Valley of the Dolls\"?", "answer": "Jacqueline Susann", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b492", "question": "Which country were the 1896 Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ea", "question": "On Homeland Security's Color-Coded Advisory System, what does the color blue mean?", "answer": "Guarded, second from the bottom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6003958357a0e35c43f83894", "question": "What is the term for reproducing a texture by laying paper over it and rubbing it with a pencil or crayon?", "answer": "Frottage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdab46f0b8cce1e6fda7047", "question": "As of 2020, what company makes the Butterfinger bar?", "answer": "Ferrero", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15d", "question": "Mother Teresa was awarded the 1979 Nobel Prize for what?", "answer": "Peace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf85", "question": "St Apollonia is the patron saint of what?", "answer": "Dentistry and Toothache", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fed2bbaec223966ae8f8911", "question": "What is the name of the smelly green ghost in \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Slimer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa74f73838c5c8a417f37", "question": "What is the fear of long words known as?", "answer": "Hippopotomostrosesquippedaliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b292", "question": "What piece of technology did IBM develop in 1973 that they nicknamed Winchester?", "answer": "A disk drive", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66be9a5bfecdd737e088b", "question": "What's the name of the punctuation that combines a question mark and an exclamation point?", "answer": "Interrobang", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a707", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Peach State\"?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e94d21b5ea27d7a1303aed8", "question": "What two players were selected before Michael Jordan in the 1984 NBA Draft?", "answer": "Akeem Olajuwon and Sam Bowie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938e", "question": "Who played the role of Jim Stark in the movie \"Rebel Without a Cause\"?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6659fa5bfecdd737e0861", "question": "Who were the first people to use currency?", "answer": "Lydians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937ec2a08d98002fdd633b8", "question": "Which singer's autobiography is titled \"Take It Like a Man\"?", "answer": "Boy George's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76b", "question": "Who steers the shell and motivates the rowers in a crew race?", "answer": "Coxswain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc1375469bb8041d07a07f", "question": "What did the \"lemon campaign\" advertise in the 60's?", "answer": "Volkswagen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb6", "question": "Which Greek island was the center of the Minoan civilization?", "answer": "Crete", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e54", "question": "What European city do Ethan Hawke and Julie Delpy wander in the movie \"Before Sunrise\"?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d2", "question": "How many claws does a domestic cat have?", "answer": "18", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339125", "question": "\"Samson and Delilah\" is an opera by which French composer?", "answer": "Camille Saint-Sa\u00ebns", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6e4", "question": "Who invented the box that psychologists use to shock rats?", "answer": "B. F. Skinner", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca9b", "question": "Sophophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Learning or knowledge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb611a5dad637d903c882d", "question": "What is the Golden Gate Bridge named after?", "answer": "Golden Gate was named after the narrow, 300-foot-deep Golden Gate Strait which flows underneath it.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133978f", "question": "What did Def Leppard drummer Rick Allen lose in a 1984 auto accident?", "answer": "An arm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600242bc4be4723ccac2218b", "question": "Which French novelist wrote the seven-volume novel \"In Search of Lost Time\" (often translated as \"Remembrance of Times Past\")?", "answer": "Marcel Proust", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffcfbd49dc5ec6cd98a8318", "question": "Who painted \"The Starry Night\"?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e23", "question": "Who's the most famous resident of Mr. Peebles' pet shop?", "answer": "Magilla Gorilla", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b1", "question": "What was Leonard Nimoy's character's name in Star Trek?", "answer": "Mr. Spock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbea56ce05a3942286ef4", "question": "Which rock band performed at President Bill Clinton's first inauguration?", "answer": "Fleetwood Mac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a0", "question": "What movie starred Johnny Depp as Willy Wonka?", "answer": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3f3", "question": "What never works at night and requires a gnomon to tell the time?", "answer": "A sundial", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f70bba9e54d890926f6d7", "question": "In which city is the majority of the Las Vegas Strip located?", "answer": "Paradise -- The majority of the 4.2-mile stretch of glittering lights is actually located in the neighboring town of Paradise.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff20eab31a458464a93c428", "question": "Who composed \"Ride of the Valkyries\"?", "answer": "Richard Wagner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe771bfeec85e375820b2fe", "question": "Where are sky burials still performed?", "answer": "Tibet", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae1e", "question": "In which decade was the Three Mile Island nuclear disaster?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c0", "question": "What Al Pacino movie portrayed a bank robbery on August 22, 1972?", "answer": "Dog Day Afternoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a63a32ebb971c1417fb9b", "question": "Who played the Girl on the Motorcycle in the 1968 film of same name?", "answer": "Marianne Faithful", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b027", "question": "Who was the 36th US President?", "answer": "Lyndon Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971f", "question": "Which Australian played James Bond?", "answer": "George Lazenby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c86b877e98cb977789e4", "question": "Where can you see the petroglyphs of Newspaper Rock?", "answer": "Petrified Forrest National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594d07261a1c922dd1ac64b5", "question": "Who says, \"Th-th-th-that's all folks!\"?", "answer": "Porky Pig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab29", "question": "What ocean is the island of Madagascar located in?", "answer": "Indian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5be580c25415ba52ed6f0ab8", "question": "Doha is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Qatar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ee", "question": "Who played the role of Daniel in the 1984 film \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "Ralph Macchio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce4", "question": "What fashion brand was co-founded by artist Justin Timberlake?", "answer": "William Rast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c61d", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Chlorine?", "answer": "Cl", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf1", "question": "In what year was famous designer Giorgio Armani born?", "answer": "1934", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339155", "question": "What is a platinum record awarded for?", "answer": "An LP selling a million copies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a7", "question": "Which artist's \"Impression Sunrise\" gave its name to the whole impressionist movement?", "answer": "Claude Monet's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b3f901dd7bf43be5e7b8", "question": "How did jaywalking get its name?", "answer": "\"Jay\" was a term for a naive person", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a6f720565ad31a57c7e3", "question": "What is considered the turning point of World War II in Europe?", "answer": "Battle of Stalingrad", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59c1cde77bd84c0ea43ad431", "question": "In Norse mythology, what did Odin trade an eye for?", "answer": "Wisdom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7fd", "question": "In what layer of the Earth's atmosphere is Antarctica's famed \"ozone hole\"?", "answer": "Stratosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab1e", "question": "Which coast of Australia is Sydney located on?", "answer": "East", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e80351de59ea584496fe9c", "question": "Dodie Smith wrote what book that later became a very popular Disney film?", "answer": "The Hundred and One Dalmatians", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59029f95cad1ec93f27df761", "question": "What continent does yerba mate originates from?", "answer": "South America", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339819", "question": "The I-V-vi-IV chord progression is commonly referred to by what alliterative name?", "answer": "Pop-punk progression", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e93", "question": "What movie did the villain Verbal Kint appear in?", "answer": "The Usual Suspects", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133becd", "question": "How many Witches are in a coven?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062a58c9d816e292245c17", "question": "What is Judy Chicago's most well-known work?", "answer": "Regarded as the first epic feminist artwork, \"The Dinner Party\" functions as a symbolic history of women in Western civilization.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e6", "question": "On what date did the Menendez murders take place?", "answer": "August 20, 1989", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b0", "question": "Which fictional park is the home of Yogi Bear?", "answer": "Jellystone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb0882bcf631c2414a13b5a", "question": "What does \"Valar Morghulis\" mean in High Valyrian?", "answer": "All men must die", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1f6", "question": "Hoa Lo Prison was more commonly called what by American POWs?", "answer": "The Hanoi Hilton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65d3e1f3c0ead6880d619", "question": "What Enron CEO took the company to financial disaster?", "answer": "Kenneth Lay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecd94eec223966ae8f88de", "question": "The big screen villain of which film required the use of 51 puppeteers?", "answer": "\"Little Shop of Horrors\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133983e", "question": "Who won an Oscar for her portrayal of a young dancer in the movie \"Black Swan\"?", "answer": "Natalie Portman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067fbfff9c0647b50a8087", "question": "Overall, how many medals did US swimmer Michael Phelps win at the 2016 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "6", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9026301dd7bf43be5e869", "question": "What is difference between Cognac and brandy?", "answer": "Cognac is a brandy only produced in Cognac, France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab145dbaab681b09292173", "question": "What year did Volkswagen introduce the Golf GTI?", "answer": "1976", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0d", "question": "What are the two fruit juices in a cosmopolitan?", "answer": "Cranberry and lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c43", "question": "Who wrote \"The Cat in the Hat\" and \"Green Eggs and Ham\"?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad76", "question": "Whose tomb was found in the Valley of the Kings in Egypt?", "answer": "Tutankhamun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390db", "question": "Who was Humbert Humbert's obsession in the novel \"Lolita\"?", "answer": "Dolores Haze", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b58b01dd7bf43be5e7d1", "question": "What was Big Ben renamed to in 2012?", "answer": "Elizabeth Tower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c36d", "question": "What valuable product is obtained from the sturgeon?", "answer": "Caviar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febd43a7e83c707845b215a", "question": "What famous actor turned down the role of Trinity in film \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Sandra Bullock turned down the role because she had the understanding that Will Smith was in the film.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1fa", "question": "Which country were the 1992 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392eb", "question": "In the 1991 movie \"Thelma and Louise\" who plays the part of Thelma?", "answer": "Geena Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a19c", "question": "Grace Metalious wrote which famous novel and TV show by the same name?", "answer": "Peyton Place", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133894d", "question": "What William Golding novel tells the story of a group of boys cast away on a desert island?", "answer": "Lord of the Flies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb2", "question": "What disease killed 20,000 Parisians in 1832?", "answer": "Cholera", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cb8", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional \"The Fraternal Order of Loons\" fraternity?", "answer": "Coach", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a64", "question": "What spirit is the comic book nemesis of Casper, the Friendly Ghost?", "answer": "Spooky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133900b", "question": "Who was King of Mycenae and Commander of the Greek forces in the Trojan War?", "answer": "Agamemnon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8bc5ec223966ae8f8842", "question": "Dr. Gregory House shares the same home address as which other fictional character?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes (albeit in different countries)", "category": "entertainment"}]